Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree:

Anusha Ravishankar () Featured

Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Client Servicing, Programming, Mongo DB, Jenkins, React. Js, Eclipse, Java



Current Designation: Engineer - Software Development

(Contract)

Current Company: Bharat Electronics Limited

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Mangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: software developer,mongodb,react.js,core java,javafx,css,GIT,SIP,VOIP

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Hard-working professional with proven creative thinking, language, and service skills. Aiming to leverage my abilities to successfully fill the Software Engineer role at your company. Engineer with diverse experience in various domain of Software Industry. I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

Work Experience

Bharat Electronics Limited as Engineer - Software Development (Contract) Jun 2018 to Till Date

- * Implementing interactive network management portal using ReactJS for configuring Node in a PBX Network
- * Implemented functionalities of a web based voice logger system which involves call recording, backup in different formats.

system monitoring and backing up history using java/angularjs and Apache derbyDB

- * Implemented SIP and RTP protocols for developing SIP RFC features(Call transfer, Call forward, conference, Instant Messaging) in the operator console using JAIN SIP API
- * Developing a Elementary Management System(Web Application) using ReactJS and Java, used for managing network elements in a PBX exchange
- * Developed Operator Console using JavaFX for communicating with other gateways and also includes features like Phone

book(using MongoDB), Chat message, call logging, call recording, in a PBX system used for military communication

EMC Software services Ltd as Associate Project Manager

Mar 2016 to Jun 2017

Handled various projects related to information storage techniques ,involving different products of EMC like DataDomain, VNX to name a few. Was involved in management phases right from product installation to product deployment at the client location Involved in every phase of project management including project initiation, planning and execution

Wipro Technologies as Project Engineer

Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

- * I underwent training in Web Technologies including JAVA, SERVLETS, HTML5, JAVASCRIPT and ORACLE 11gXE Database.
- * Was involved in development of a web based project pertaining to online Interview Tracking System (involving management of candidates and interviews through online portal) as a part of Wipro Fresher course, using Java Enterprise Edition technologies like Servlets, JSP, EJB.
- * Worked on tools specific to Database like Oracle SQL developer, Eclipse Mars

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Science Engineering) from Visvesvariah Technological university in 2015

PG: in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Core JAVA, JAVA-FX			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JAIN SIP API, JAVA-Concurrency			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Angular js(Version 1.1)			0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Derby DB			0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
* IDE - Netbeans 8.2			2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Eclipse-WebEE			0 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
* OS- Linux (Ubuntu 16.04) and Windows 8			2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)
React.js		0	0 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
Gluon Scene Builder (JAVAFX IDE)		0	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Kannada	Proficient			
Hindi	Beginner			

Projects

Project Title: PBX System
Client: Bharat Electronics
Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jun 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Developed a Desktop phone application for military communication PBX project. The softphone is compatible with both Windows and Linux systems. It was built with technologies like JAVAFX for all user interface development and JAIN SIP API for all backend communication. The soft-phone supports various functionalities like instant messaging, phone features like transfer, hold, call forward, black list. It also supports call logging, saving contacts on phonebook. The underlying protocol used was application layer SIP protocol and TCP/UDP for network layer. The voice communications are through RTP protocol. Application can support multiple calls at once with a in built queuing system. Currently building a web version of the same

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time